My mike...good cool so,
I'm sousa giuliano I'm going-to be here talking about logic apps and, ...
find the...microsoft and I'll talk about logic cups too, yeah,
so, just as a quick reminder and please be shared...submit your valuations it's
very helpful for us to get feedback about what we can do better so this is a minor so,
today what I'm going to talk about is I'll give a background
of the story of integration inside a manager I'll...overview of as your
app service and what that means for logic gaps and we have a couple demos
plan as well we're going to give you some background on the architecture of logic
gaps how they work kind of where they came
from and what you can do to use them more effectively so?
Integration inside of as your.
In march just about a month ago...released asher apps service so hopefully some of
you had a chance to hear about that to see the talk I think there's actually a couple...and
address service so I'm going to cover that very briefly but the other things I want to call
out is today we have api management also in as...as well as
biztalk services is that jade last year actually and,
we are working very tightly with the community to
really hear from you guys as to what the important things to invest in our
so, all come back to this but really we're trying to be feedback driven in
...development so, we've reached out through newsletters through blog posts ...to
hear from you guys about what the most important things to work on are also at w pc
will be hangout...to add the best partner integration solutions so stay
tuned for that so building apps inside of microsoft as
...brings a lot of great capabilities that you wouldn't get from building on
prime solution so,
for as your apps service we want to give you ways to deliver applications at
massive scale with tens of millions of concurrent users at a time as well
we want to make it easy for you to deliver and read your code very quickly and,
deliver updates into the running clap at
the same time we give you insights into exactly what's happening...application
so all these things would be a bit more difficult if you weren't running on asher but,
as you're brings us to natively before the release of
asher app service we had these three services available to you as
...websites measure mobile services and
biz talk servicesI'm going to spend just a couple minutes talking about this
talk services and just by show of hands how many of you are familiar with is
talk so, I would say at least half so that's good because biz
talk is in many ways the inspiration for logic apps but,
it isn't a direct one-to-one translation so we learn a lot of things with
the biz talk services release that we did last year?
For example,
we validated that bringing integration into the cloud is actually a key scenario that you
care about as well...having hybrid solutions is also very important but
the same time we found that there were some key feature problems and gaps with
is talk services so, really what we're going to work on through logic
apps is to solve these key feature gaps in many cases we have as well
as to bring new capabilities that would not have impossible with is talk historically.
One of the biggest challenges with is talk is the learning curve so if
you come and you try to install biztalk server that alone is going to be
...pretty steep learning
curve much less actually using it so this has been a key
...point and what really resulted in was a sort of wall when you tried
to develop for biz talkyou had to go through this...of repo over
it even get anything done and as result what we found was people
were instead of delivering...simple
easy-to-use this talk solutions they were doing a lot of hacking and the reason that they
...doing hacking is because it's really easy to geo just
...hundred lines of code and orchestrate a couple api is to bring some things together but,
this is really what you want to be doing with your time you don't want to
geo just write a couple lines of code and then five weeks later
some is going to come back and have you add a little more to that code and then, you know,
somebody else and have to maintain it and...rewrite it...just turns into
...the snowball so instead of actually using biz talk because
...was so hard you would end up writing this code yourself that's where we want logic apps...
comment so instead of learning curve like that red-line...a you'll instead see
...curve more like this so our goal is that you can very easily
deliver integration solutions in microsoft manager by using logic
it starts out very simple and we'll go through some pretty simple demos here today
but if you need additional more our if you need more our if you need more additional capabilities
and it does become a little more complex but at a very gradual rate it's not like there's
this big clip for wall...to jump over in order to understand how to use integration.
Going hand-in-hand with this
our vision our road map for large gaps is democratize
integration that's a very key point because we see
there been a lot of developers out here there's a lot of people who did not raise their hands when they said they use
this talk that is who we want to be able to take advantage of logic in the
cloud because you guys that didn't raise your hands you would never have
even probably considered setting up of this talk server and, you know,
using that...the cloud running that both logic apps is very easy if you
to get started and to be able to use cashmere to run your business processes
so, that's really what we're going to focus on now another key point is that we
see ourselves as trying to be a leader in the space so dispel that acronym
that's integration platform as a service so that means we're going
...your logic for-you rather than you...server and deploy
uaw workflow into that server and maintain...a manage yourself
instead we will manage most everything for you on your behalf and,
you will only have to worry about managing the code that you actually want to write yourself.
The third point is we are working on creating a rich ecosystem where
...where people can bring the...solutions deploy them into
a gallery inside of asher and other people can take advantage of it so,
with the various types applications we have api
...and large-cap you'll be able to submit them and take advantage of them the ones
...have been submitted by other people so at the end of the day we see this
as a very exciting time for people who want to develop applications,
you know, the key for an application is connecting to your customers so,
you need a way where you can empower your employees both yourselves and other people
in your organizations to be able to deliver these apps very quickly and
in agile manner...internet scale so that's our vision for
logic apps and more broadly for address service so what
we've done is we've brought together some of the key capabilities that already exists in as
your added some new ones together for apps service on the for components
...service are web apps mobile apps logic apps
and api apps and hopefully some of you had a chance to attend all up
...talk but,
in case you didn't I'll just go through these briefly and then we'll spend the rest the talk talking about logic gaps.
Before I do that I want to actually give a brief overview of some of the
key new advocate abilities that we've release in the last year that you may not be too familiar
so the first one is I often get asked do you have auditing inside
...you actually track all the operations that happen can I go and see that and the
answer is yes to all of those so any management operation that happens through adj or through the
...portal through the api through...we actually track
all of those so you can come back later and you can see who has done what and
...to your services as the running at the same time you want to be able to
have more granular control over the services that you've deployed you
may want one developer to be able to develop one particular solution but not have access to the
vietnam's that run your businesses core processes you can do that with
...access control which was also
released last year at the same time you need to be able to manage the deployments
lifecycle of your services we do that with as
resource manager they're so for most of these there are also other
talk small there have been are the talks in build so, definitely check those out if
you'd like to learn more as well we have full management api so all
of the things that we show you today that you can do with logic gaps you can also do via
...rest api which we fully documented as well as through partial commandments that
allow you to manage the creation and deletion of measure resources and finally I get asked a
lot about will this be available on tram and the answer is yes?
We work to take all
the capabilities that are available on as your and bring that into each iteration of the asher
...for those of you...are familiar measure...is basically imagine running a little
many as you're inside your own data center so everything that you see today
and any of the other as a...talks will eventually be available inside as your
...isn't available quite yet but over time we bring those capabilities down it
does like a little bit behind because it's non-transfer...we have to ship boxes as opposed to code?
So, as your apps service better together and
is one low-price for all of these capabilities that we're going to talk about
today and we have a number of built-in connectors
even take advantage of so with as your apps service you will want to be able
to build applications that take dependencies and other services out there so, for example,
if your consumer facing application you may not may want to be able to talk to twitter or
dropbox?
If...its price
...application you may want to talk to dbtwo or web sphere
...a probably existed before I was born.
So, you can take advantage of all of these together through connectors
in addition we have a number of protocol connectors that you can also take advantage of
...you want to be able to use ftp
...whenever process...we actually give you
clean rest interfaces on top of those to be able to make those calls
so from app service we give you a bridge into any of these other worlds
...existed for a long-time you don't have to take all of your logic move...all to the
cloud all at once they'll...very...if you want...do a bile means try but,
in the meanwhile if you don't want to if you want
to a piecemeal definitely you can take advantage of api connectors finally on this
slidewe have a number of biztalk services you can take advantage of so
our strategy for biz talk specifically has been to break apart all of
that giant monolithic you deploy that would take three days just a setup we've actually
broken apart decomposed into a number of clean api surfaces that you
can use individually edit only requires you to install what you need so instead of having
...this massive monolithic you can now take advantage of just say
that extract functionality that this aac has for ex path or just stwo inside of
this talk so that's one of the key points there now for the for app types
we have web apps which allow you to deploy web interfaces directly into
the cloud and supports a wide variety of applications so everything that we talk about
...supports these five languages and it means that you don't have to
use dot net I assume since what build the vast majority of you love dot net but,
if you don't then you can definitely take advantage of other technologies as
well mobile applications are great because they allow you to build a mobile back-end
for your web our for your mobile app so if you want, for example,
to be able to have a scenario where I can
write mobile app when something's going to click a button it goes off into the cloud and does something
I'll show kind of demo that at the end you can do that using mobile apps?
The third pieces logic apps which is what this talk is mostly going to be about
and that allows you to without having to write code execute business processes in the
cloud.
And, finally the api apps which are those interfaces that I was talking about these are the
clean rest...all the functionality that unique so if you want to
be able todo...have a connector to your only api as you can do that using api
app...great about api apps is they have a consistent standard for how they
describe themselves so api apps you swagger which is a open-source
format...a meta data description format describes all of the rest calls
and api has and all the demos that will show you take advantage of the swagger to be able to
...ui appropriately?
Finally the biztalk
...vone which is the best talk services
and we've made a lot of improvements upon so those key feature gaps
us talking about earlier we think we've made a lot of progress on so I don't expect
you to read all this right now you can look
the slides later but the point here is all those red boxes that was
...vone and with
app services today with both this talk and logic apps we've turned a lot of
those green there's still a little work left to be done if there wasn't then I probably would have
a job anymore but it will work on that and based on your feedback
will take those improvements going forward so before jump into the demo there's one more point I want to
cover and that is people have come to me and they've asked me who do you expect to be able to use this
and the answer is anybody who uses azerbaijan so if you're a developer if you're
...ip pro and you're familiar with as you can come to the portal then you should be able to take advantage of
logic...to develop and deliver your business processes but and this time we are not
targeting consumers so we definitely don't expect my mom to go to the
...portal and to write a simple process that would be kind of crazy because as a
...you have a subscription...requires you see a bunch of stuff but...that svm and none of that stuff would
really make sense right so we are thinking about this going
forward but for today when we talk about logic apps we're talking about the solution as a part
of as your that is focused on developers ninety process so now I can switch over
to the demo and...computer hasn't completely gone to sleep.
So, what you're going to see here is this is the new editor portal just a
curiosity how many people have actually played with the new portal
as this thing right here wow most of you that's great so,
logic apps as well as both the answers capabilities are only available in the new portal
so, if you went to the full poorly wouldn't be able to see that but so, yeah, so, in order to create a
logic...you can go to plus new down here this gives you the create experience with
a number of categories all of the...service is together
in this unify place called...mobile and you can see here the web apps
...mobile apps logic gaps and api
...so you could create all those here together and when you create a logic at all you have to do is
...a name so, I'll just bill
large gap and you have to choose the app service plan now the
...service plan is very important because that represents the thing you're
paying for the plan is you can kind of think of it as the virtual machine
that all of your various apps to run on and...great about that is you can deploy as many apps
...you want into the same plan without having to pay ascent more so,
that that's a great capability and you can of course scale that independent of the app so if you
want ten instances of this
...one instance you can do that in the...here now let's go ahead and click create?
And, that...go off and take a few
seconds so instead of using that one I'll just go to a blank one that I
...created and this then loads up this is
the blade as we call them for...apps at the top of the
blade you can see we summarize the most important information about it so you can see,
for example, the name...state what is endpoint is the
endpoint is interesting because that allows you to invoke it from a
say mobile application directly as well as the plan so this is the thing I'm
...and the number...had etc so I can just come here and click
edit and this will open up the portal designer so this is
a simple experience that we've created to make it easy for you without having
to write code to create a business process.
Now the first thing that you do inside a logic app is you add a recurrence so,
I can just click on that here.
Sorry I misspoke so it isn't necessarily the person you have to do
because you can actually use many different types of triggers so recurrence is just one type of trigger but,
you could also, for example, trigger whenever you got a new tweet or whenever somebody...a button
...application all those are possible but for this purpose
demo I'll just user occurrence and I'll have this run say every minute.
And, I will actually click the buttons that
I try to click on so then I've created so my large-cap
who run based on this trigger the next thing that you do is you add a
series of actions into your application so this gallery on the
right-hand side here this shows you all of the api apps that I've already provision
into my resource group these api apps could be ones that came from the gallery in this case,
you know, dropbox and facebook offices sixty-five these are ones that we've already published
to the gallery that you can take advantage of yourself but they also could be api apps that
you create yourself that publish your own api from your organization
but I've added that on so the first thing that I have to do when I
add a card or certain cards is aft authorized them so this uses the standard
offload where it takes me to a twitter web page and I click
authorize and that grant's me a token from twitter to be able to
use the twitter api so now when I called twitter from this workflow
...act on behalf of my user identity?
The next thing that you see here is a list of all the actions that we've exposed as a part of the
twitter api...you can see I can...these guys and get details on exactly what
these api czar and in fact we give you a wide variety of api
as we kind of show you the most important the top you can see here all the other api is that twitter
has so I can get that information but for the purposes of this demo we're actually going to
do is we're going to search twitter for tweets about large gaps and
archive them to my dropbox that way I can come back later and I can do a search on top
of than I can see what people have been saying about logic apps.
You can imagine you could very easily do this for your own company in just a few minutes so when I click on
an action I see the input parameters to that particular action search
...is simple ones because it just takes one field.
So, this click logic apps so now this will go off and
the search for large-cap so the next thing I'm going to do is all add a
dropbox connector just like the twitter connector this requires authorization with
the dropbox api so it will show up a button and once I
...that it will then show me again the list of actions that dropbox has so.
That I already authorize that so didn't even ask me this time.
Shows me list of actions and then for the action I want you today
all upload files so this will upload the tweet content into my dropbox.
As with the tweet I see the
list of parameters to this dropbox api now.
This all is meta data-driven so we have not written a single-line
of custom ui to work with these api...instead.
These api is all
expose swagger which is that common rest metadata documentation
format inside the swagger they contain all the information needed to draw this so,
for example, the dropbox swagger says it has an operation called upload file
the upload file operation has parameters like file path content encoding and whether or not to
overwrite
and even this the meta data comes from this description comes from that
metadata as well so for the file path all this type logic gaps.
Dot txt.
for the content now this is where it really the our of logic apps comes in is I
can flow the data from the first step to the second one rather than having statically
...I can open this drop down right here it shows me here
these outputs from that previous steps you can see the twitter connector outputs taxed
and outputs the treated by so I can select them from here so I'm just going to select
...drops in a token and,
we'll talk a bit more about the language in a little while but for now...click...
Or click the check marketing and then I will click safe.
So, now it's going to happen is this logic apple run every minute
you will pull twitter for any new tweets about logic
gaps and then we'll upload them into a file called logic apps
...txt in my dropbox so let's switch over to dropbox which I have
...tab and see so you can see here eleven seconds ago there
is a new file called logic abstract txt added and as you can
see somebody here probably treated about outside their...
app so that's great they haven't even seen the whole demo...excited so,
all close this so one of the things that you may have notices wrong with this
flow though is this will actually only take.
One tweet at a time which isn't very efficient and in fact because
the file path is the same is going to keep overriding that one file.
So, instead what you can do design come in and I can edit this action again.
And, inside the action I'm going to add what we call repeat so that
will iterate over a list of things so I can come back here and say repeat over
...and into this field I will pass
this array from the previous step so I can open this drop down here.
And, this flows the body from this request into the into
each iteration of this dropbox nectar so instead of having
the static filename...I'm going to have it be the
idea of the tweet so whenever you reference
and item from that iteration from the repeat it's just a function called
repeat item and then I'll do tweet id in addition I can, you know,
a pen things the beginning or the end of this field so for dropbox I want
actually put everything into a folder so I'll just call this my folder so I'm just constructing a
path here right and then at the end of the path all do dot txt so this
...do is we'll put the tweets into a folder called my folder with the idea of the tweet
...the filename and then for the content you can type these expressions but instead if I just want to be
able to drop in say the fields directly I can do that you see we've
...populated...with the expression you need so you don't necessarily need to learn all
about these languages you can just drop them directly into the fields here.
And, then you can also of course and other text...site side the
...I could say was treated by.
And, then it has the person was treated by I can change any of these other fields.
...I click okay.
So, there you go successful so now what's happened is this updated logic
app has been deployed into the cloud all I've done is I've just modified a few fields
in the ui and it's already it's up there it's running.
So, I'm going to close this out real quick and show you one other
view so this see right here this shows you all of the
...the...that this logic app is executed so,
for example, at twelve-fifty for it when often
it did something so I can click this and I can see all the actions that it took along with each
action I can see the exact inputs and outputs of that call
in this case let's look at what the twitter connector returned and I can see here that
...will have return say list of tweets.
So, you can see here I can see all of the tweets that people has had about logic
apps pretty sure I saw my name here that.
I can close this out and if I go now to my dropbox hopefully by now so you
see my folder was added
if I open this up I will see the tweets that have recently
come in about large gaps thirty seconds ago if I open up one of these.
You see it has now both the that pretext as well as who treated it so,
you can definitely combine as many different fields together is you want and you can use this
...to construct a great business process.
So, now something failed somewhere we don't need to investigate that right now.
So, just to recapwhat I've shown is how you can very easily build
a business process in just a few minutes by using the ui in the portal?
Now the key concept here was that we are flowing
data between each of these steps and this creates what we call-in implicit dependency
so that dropbox step when it executes depends on the twitter step
successfully executing and because you're using the twitter data inside of the
dropbox step it knows that the first one
...execute finish and then dropbox myaccess acute however if you
prefer to a wire up your dependencies explicitly so you say I want this to
execute than that than that you can and we give you
an explicit syntax to do that you can use depends on.
Finally you can build even more complex expressions which ilya will cover
and his section the demo to do things like when something fails do an action.
The other concept that I covered was repeating so this allowed us to
execute as many times as there was an item in a list is a for each right.
And, you can also imagine we have a function called range that just returns
back-end array of numbers so you could do just your old-style
for into I equals zero et cetera et...inside of a logic app as well.
Finally I didn't quite cover this earlier
...as well is we have conditions and what's interesting about conditions is they allow
you to the either conditionally execute or not execute so
with that all handed over to ilya and he'll talk about the architecture...gaps.
Hello, everyone my name is media and I
am as resource manager architect and logic cops architect and you guys
short ca grade them of logic...right so every fan beautiful
lies ui but what we build actually is available the rest api
we have a concept of a definition you can actually serialized entire workflow you
build in ui and chicken your source code and use it later so I'm going to show all
these details about language and about how it can use visual studio to actually...in your
project but let's step back a little bit and talk about the edge resource manager so
leisure source manager allow you to artistry deployments
of various resources in the cloud so you may actually a so
markers univision demo how easy to create two hundred nodes
gloucester less than five minutes that's actually...of the iceberg we can actually
create hundred-thousand offer resources in five minutes as long as
you have subscription capable called this number of resource based on the what
...so we have this great engine and then we decide it will be cool
to actually expose it to all customers and let them run
...on business logic so that's why we build this logic
...engine and you can actually find that it's very similar to what
we explores
...resource manager as well so if you guys at the use like templates or you try to use like
rest api that something similar and this is something we
...actually you guys try as well so...same engine we share most of the
...it is highly distributed highly available.
Be try to do as best as possible...no failures and like deliver, for example,
each action have certain guarantees but
that's not really exactly the same as the measure source measure, for example,
the first think of ed...the extend the language to include more
functions so if you look and editor source manager functions is only eight of them and most
of them about the stink manipulations for logic up
...support for logical operations for moffett...be
...support for json transformations so you can actually use this logic...
in your workflow definition in order to like pipe information across different
actions perform transformations summer logic and then it's all in very
...language what we also did in logic cops
engine we'll let them speak natively
...reston points so we...betters
...is like basic...certificate or both so if you have
...json address base and point
right now most likely you can use it within the logic
...engine already without any modifications and if you have
like xml based or maybe not very restful api you can create
an api connector which you can use in order to
...perform this little bit of like transformation or make
...like restful so you can immediately start consuming...within the logic ox.
Logic cops also have unique concept of the triggers so if you look and
editor resource manager all this deploys
...manually you can go in ui and click the button or you can use like our
...submit...new template deployment in logic cops we introduce the concept of
that triggers, triggers can be very simple is just run this
thing can every fifteen seconds or is can be complex...like each certain
endpoint get the output validate certain properties,
for example,
you can actually use dieter connector which steven show early
as...three gear when I can that each at tweet that api search for...find
someone some negative to be the bite my company using...knowledge is if it's cross
...threshold then I can execute the rest of my workflow in order, for example,
like customer support to reach out the person and provide the support?
So, what we try to do with this language
is to make it a simple us possible and remover baiter to
answer and trite these does well this is the simplest?
Actual logical up workflow definition it is
only for top-level properties you actually need to know.
In fact all of them optional.
You can have workflow...out parameters leaguers options or
no output...toll and...perfectly valid workflow which do enough and.
Let's talk about the individual
...in details so what's the parameters so the idea is basically you have
the workflow and its execute certain steps and what you want you actually won the
peep these steps based on your different like
...environment or uonechange some...is
...a certain situation that's why we have a parameters so you keep your workflow static and
you can supply parameters file or like provide parameter
single-line in a way that you don't actually need to change of workflow definition
...it's actually very useful if you can consider chicken in your...
definition two-source control and then you have separate files, for example,...production or...
environments we also provide in like basic support all of the parameters validation of the
explores the concept of the type we can
...like streak integer of an object we also allow you to specify default
...or list of about allow it well it's?
The next concept is that the...which I mentioned earlier
...currents they basically run every fifteen seconds fifty
...how you configuredyou can actually have multiple
triggers within the same workload definition right so, for example,
you may actually can see there are...of workflow
...is betas factor actually I need to trigger but they actually work
...the another interesting concept is actually that trigger is a stateful so you can
use the previous trigger execution in order to make a decision so,
for example, let's say you have a
...which fire every time new...sharpen...books and you try to...to,
for example, one drive three-year fire you have a list of files but unfortunately of workflow can
...transfer or files it once so you have to do
it one by one so you can actually use a state within that
...in order to save...files which you already process and you can actually make it fully
stateful or another example could be like...time stamp let's
say a princess chunk of work up to ten am and next execution io
...says from ten...to eleven I am so trigger stateful it's very it's very
crucial for certain us scenarios another thing we actually have an...is a concept of
...conditions, conditions ox does a post condition
they basically will run off to be perform and the rest http
call in order to evaluate that...you should be fired or not so,
for example, previously I mention how you can use to
...connector in order to reach out to
...and all...that tweet and see if...a machine negative about your company you can
actually use conditions in order to say jeopardy gears
...get two-thirty get the sentiment on elements and then you can use...condition in order
to compare how negative score is looks like if it's super but then you can use one
...in negative then you can use another workflow?
Next...is.
Options sorry about that so
...is a set of steps which will be executed each time the workflow
is workflows...option have a dependencies order
of execution is infer but this dependencies but if to action
don't have any dependence is you can assume it's run in parallel in this case the logic
...engines provide at best effort to
execute your workflow as fast as possible and in most cases
...your rest api very...can take up this
...few seconds likeit...of also conditions
but this is actually preconditions they will be evaluated each time
than auction is about the execute in order to decide should this action execute or
base keep I will show...demo how we can actually use it later in order to perform
an action...if something fail right so
they're not necessarily want to execute action of somethin' succeed we can actually use
...condition in order to compensate or have an action which only run
...previous step fail?
Likeit...actions also have a state
that fully stateful the state he's unique for each is individual...
for execution and you can use this step so, for example, achieve like scenario
...a want to use measures source manager deployment I one of
...when it's completed and I want to send light text message to myself
...no my deployment them in this case I will create the workflow I'll have to
...the first action
...initiate of process of a template deployment the deployment resources
in larger then I will wait until it's completed by using the stateful
mcneese and the last step will be just some text message I will actually show it how we can
send text message out later.
Steven already mention each actual have a concept
...repeat items we allow you to the...action for released
often do you...items like an array but what's interesting that
an action can be...just http action option can be
actually three-year another workflow as a result if you have a list of
items and you have another workflow you...actually combine these two concept together...
very powerful thing when you opponent...the list of items and
each...will be processor child workflow and you can have separate diffusion files
...chicken them source control and them use them independent.
And, the last thing is that template language expressions you already so some of the
expressions scene ui don't hide them we actually allowed them user to use
they basically an extension of the like a json so the basic
...of the workload definition is
...file...but...allow you to express
...and transformations certain conditions certain expressions so the
add this concept of template language expressions they basically done...sort of
...start with the symbol...and you can also...of the string interpolation
...so this little things allow you to perform like math for
...community and manipulations just like
in javascript all this template languish expressions looks like a functions
with a parameters and you can use dot or index in order
to extract properties so they think it's actually very simple you can actually see a few examples
...the screen now let me go back to ...them and visual studious so let me tell what's,
what's going to happen so I have a simple website with currently
running and measure and I'm going to create a
...allergic up feature video perform the endpoint
...each will basically try to being my website every fifteen seconds
...succeed or fail and if it fails it will actually send-me...message
because I always want to know that my website is healthy and every time software on I want to see the
...and that will take some action so I let me go back to
...ok so here's my
website is very simple obstinate website is nothing specialas
a few steps aidid I already provision and api up and
...group I...to...new api up
...request a little bit of configuration what's why...that upfront
...basically allowed me to send a text messages so now if I
...back to visual studio here's the new instance of...is
...is...I can't I see itnew project and you can find.
Measure resource manager template deployment option available
under visuals csharp and the cloud so let me...ka
...release meet few options which I can use in order to like bootstrap my
initial template what is to
...specific about logic cops one is just logic up and one is
large-cap is api up for purpose of this them I will use logic of but I encourage
everyone to chide the second option it will allow you...only create the logic
offers in the from visual studio but also create and api out
...before you can create and api to connect your light known
...json and point-two something we can
...the logic up so these actually project will show you how
to create and api and combine them together so let's keep cute on...logical.
Yes, this is a simple, simple projects only have four files and
its include measure resource manager template this-is logic
of the...and its include whoops.
Whoops okay this is a resource measure template and include the parameter
file so you can have different prized...I will speech back to
different insists of visual studio...I complete my applications and then we can look at
yean details so basically this is same initial logic up's
application...resource manager template for logic cops I extended to
add in additional resource so you can see I actually have...of what
...gateway tokens I need this resource in order to all
log communication between logic cops and api
avce they basically I created at tool can inside and
api a and api...basically saying you-can call me and this is...is just
...the...to establish these
connections and then the second resource my actual logic up workflow
...perform...on the http endpoint and then perform certain validation
...conditions in order to triggered the text message so we can
see state some measure source manager parameters but you can also find that
the have same definition I described earlier
...have a single parameter gateway token which...secure...because we don't want to
...ui and...the one them make sure that the...they have a simple
...typerecurrence which fire every fifteen seconds what this means that but
now I published this workflow it will start executing and we'll start
fide in every fifteen minutes fifteen seconds.
And, have an actions which we have to
...one of this type of http?
And,...methods a and the specified and...to...this will
fire every time it to perform the gap and it's complete and
...results saying is that succeeded or fail and what's the response
code we received from the website and they have at video
...which will fire?
On the my previous step
fail this is actually interesting I using this condition expression in order to
tale I'm only interested in these step
...this expression...evaluated to true the way
how I constructed I basically take my action the http being.
I take this...scored from http request I compare it...all
k and the only...in efforts not equals.
What's interesting...workload definition I never tell that
my auction tweet there is depending on
...what's the template actually...what's the engine...actually try to
...and understand and by virtually the fact that I'm using the status
called from previous option it actually node that these action must execute offer.
Now look on the input section...include some standard parameters for
api...I need to express...host basically define
whereas my api allocated so I can construct like address your in you are in
...to call it and some...park ba using the gateway token so we can
communicate...I also tell in that I'm actually interested in the particle
operations so you so in the ui that we are
...operations available from the api apps I'm saying I'm interested in
sem message here's my request parameters for a send message I basically
put some cell phone numbers and I used in the body of a text message so
as you can also see I'm using the string interpolation
so I'm actually curious what's the status
...my website return because I'm a interested in like if it's internal
server errors like http not found so I can take a different
actions right away so let me go back to.
Portal and draws to my resource group.
Here's...build them resources which I.
Ok.
Here's my resource growth as you can see I have for sources here this is my video
...share provision previously I also have a gateway which participating
communications and...secure I also have my logic
top site being which is currently running and more
...website and I have website itself let's go check the logic of itself.
...if it loads.
as you can see we already have some history of executions one is particularly
...right now but let's go back and check the previous ones so as you can see
it so far my http action...and might video
...step resource...I say I don't want to send a text message if edifice expense
...successful so let's go back and simulate the fehler I'm going
My website and I'm going to stop so the minute I stop with my http
requests should not reach the website and hopefully in fifteen seconds I'll
get a text message.
They do show just to help a little bit I can actually try to
some music writing...I'm keep getting the text messages and that say that
...website being...start escort these forbidden.
And, if you scroll to the history ...of the runs I can actually see.
The...and might video...that because I just get
the text message so what's interesting as a...mention...actually keep
...he city of the input and output request you can actually clique on the
lean can see in order to being...use get...particularly...uri and the
...output link I can actually see what's happened you cv my website is not available
and...the...that...so to...I just want to tell you that
...you see...is currently explores and.
Available as a restful api you can create your workflow you can...
into your source code you can deploy it within your application
other parts of the...template resource manager deployment and
you can will use all these great capabilities in very simple and declarative
...form right so you guys don't need to be an expert we call it's
...familiar is json javascript and you can actually
connected to things together so I think did
...you actually cover how to do the deployment...I can show it's one-man
...basically to deploy of to do is write click go deploy...choose
to resource group and click deploy so it's that easy from visual studio to just get running.
Cool so we has one more demo.
So, this is a app that I made in
cn actually and what this does is this is
invoice tracking app so every time that I add a new invoice let's say I want to
...very pi it goes and
it will actually send a text message to my phone so,
what's running back here this is the actual you...see there's the text message so,
this is the actual logic...this running up in the cloud and
I can one of the key things there is one via
a direct interaction mobile app I was able to push to the...to make it run but,
the other interesting thing here is I can modify this logic at very easily so I could come in
and I could say instead of just in a text message let's also
...post when and invoices added so I can come here and I
can click on the post message action?
And, let's go and find that the
amr group so that five four six five...six.
Six and I can just as before I can flow the data into
the step and in this case I can flow the
data not just from the previous step of from any of the previous steps right.
And, then I can click okay.
And, now what will happen is not only will the logic app
...off a text message but it will also
...amr so I can just come here and I can add one more invoice.
And, I want to a new laptop as well.
...and, you can see the...this been approved because I approve the
text message and there's the second text message I got my laptop if I go over to
the...now will be able to see there's a laptop that type ten seconds ago from
...service large gaps so without touching my mobile code that's been deployed
to my application...able to update that business process so I added more functionality to
my application very easily by just doing what talk,
you know, thirty seconds and add...the other interesting point here is this showed
a human interaction so from my phone I was able to approve that
...message and then the second step...you can...for approval workflows, for example.
So, I'll switch back to the slides.
So, to just recap as your apps services a combination of
these for things in addition this week we announced apps service
environment's and absence environments are great because they give you a way to
...ask all the different code that you have onto a compute cluster that basically you
...you own but, ...be hosted by asher and that means that you can take
that you can... to your venus so-if you have private api is that you want to
use inside your organization you still want to be able to take advantage of api apps
and web apps mobile apps you can do that by using
app service environment's...can check that out in the portal?
And, you can get started it's you can there's a free
...so you can just play with it yourself as much as you want and.
The point I want to close on before we moved to qa looks like this
of five minutes is we want to be very feedback
resin historically we would come through and we create some three-year roadmap
in be microsoft sometimes some of those things wouldn't ever actually get done but,
we're not going to do that this time this time we want to be very agile
move very quickly so we want your feedback we want to
hear from you there's a lot of channels that you can do that you can go to forums
you can email me directly asked for my business card you can go to user voice
and but we want to hear what features are most important to you and what things you need to
accomplish your business scenarios in the cloud and based on that
we will move quickly and within a few weeks or months we will get things delivered you know,
for example, I was in london two weeks ago at this...it and customer
asked for the ability to do daytime for many for strings so
...just two weeks we were able to add that functionalityinto the portal so we want
...very quickly iterate and deliver functionality...so,
here is our twitter handles you go...service dot com
and I think this time open up for questions there are three...
here so-if you...just walk up to the...that way the recording can pick up your...great?
So,...you guys showed here is like a
million times more than you can actually figure out just by using the actual
...like conditionals it's not important right there's no way to actually so,
you can actually so there's it's we hide a lot inside year.
So, yeah, you can go to the gear and you can click and you can
...condition that comes back to that...want kind...more smooth learning curve so somebody
doesn't care about conditionals they don't have to worry about it but you're right it could be a bit more discoverable.
If I can.
It's awesome that you'll be able to figure out the dependencies and therefore
there doesn't have to be declarative form of if this then do that and
conditionals can help you stop going down one path
or another and even do compensation how you going to
visualize that because right now it's kinda like a pipeline...I could have something
although at the end that has something really to do or dependency on something very much of
the beginning like are you guys working on different ui paradigms yes not only the great things about I'm
going to say windows workflowwas it was very visual and therefore you could see kind
how things would flow for all that's absolutely but ...like this yes
...absolutely I would definitely working on reading the ui so,
what we have today is kind of the simple as...going to get and, we'll come up with ways to make
it a bit more powerful and more intuitively visualize what's going on but, ...not
...appropriate you could you elaborate on the epa
environment's...thing that's what...means of it was up...on what it was...I needed
...sure so for details on...environment'sI think there's another session that
cover that but very briefly basically what that means so when you create and
...service plan today without answers environment's you basically on that the...and you can
...player code on to it without service environment's what you do is you own the whole host
...so you can attach it...venus,
for example, us that way can use a if you have express route
set up to talk to your back and service you can use that...net and,
you can also have more control...scaling so adapters environment's you can go up to far more numbers of
instances has previously could only go like ten in the portal right but since you on the whole
...at out basically as big as a hoses service can get them thanks yep hi so,
you showed earlier the...for?
Logic...yeah,
you had the http status code that...you said that was kind of something that...would
kind of just give them for free so if you're if you're reading your jason know how are you going
...that without generating it through the engine first
...aggravate...the actually exposes schema
...if you'll notice slider is in...in the visual studio
ways by builder schema section we publish schema for logic jobs
...basically the standard way how you can actually tell people like, you know,
if you have action of the type http.
Please expect that like a property...in fact actually have more probably have like start
tools we have called...message become error message and other
style but it's may not be that orbiters but I think the
jason's schema is the model how we actually out
...the one point there is if you do have your own custom api that exposes, you know,
things are not
part of our can schema and then you can I mean it sounds kind
of silly but you can just try it out and we show you all the inputs and outputs you can see exactly what your
...us that also in ui for each api app images a button which allow you to download the
entire swagger so if you familiar with this migrates declarative
...not adjacent scheme but some other...base four-month...actually tell which api
support...and what's the output well is this is how you wise but is build
a basically dynamics goal extract this information and
...just build the workload definition on top of thank...
It seemed like the conditionals were at task base levels of, you know,...failure
...can that come down to data levels so that you send...good data one-way
...data yes so basically what you can do let's say you have an action
...you have multiple dependencies you can actually fired is dependence is but in certain conditions
so you can say these only fire success is only far if some property equal
to n and this only fire some property like less than five as a result you don't
forking an action you actually perform adjoin as I mentioned the conditional
preconditions so in workload design...you basic...some stuff and you say
this go this way these go this way in our definition...action you decide,
decide what's your dependencies and...fire so within the...you make these
...but you can have like five different actions and they all compensate for different stuff,
yeah, it can it can be any runtime output that you...you
can reference anywhere in any input of any subsequent action including the conditions yes.
So,...about...you cops ...the idea to adding to development
size teaching...production...the app...we took about conditions and testing and doing
yet so I don't want to...the post treat about the...the...example,
yeah, so,...for the development pipeline with the inside visual studio...see how he had the
definition and...also had the parameter files so the typical workflow is you'd have
like one set of parameters for your dev environment another set of parameters for your stage and other for
...and then maybe for your doesn't environment would actually.
Be a valid twitter token,... or you can actually use private...the condition safe
...definite...the...so you can definitely do that
...to atom logic into.
These two now distinguish the visual studio actually already support if you actually try to deploy what is
...down you select the definition file and you actually have a list of parameter files each
parameter files can be specific to environment and then you...stick functionality based on this
There but...it just goes yes, yeah,...yeah,
so, it's always it's always running but you don't have to connected to the actual prodi pies.
Yes, so, yeah, that...question...
I guess...tests if you really going to symmetry...of the tutsis weif I'm the
You can probably add some dumb martian and just...the output and, then you can
media expose all I input output you can...see what's exactly...exactly what
received so if you replace your twitter something else wide basics save
jason to like...you can actually see exactly what you would expect thank you cool
things like guys and,
feel free to send us e-mail twitter reach out to us love to hear feedback
and evaluate the session so,
let us know how we did what we can do to get better that's important please thank you thank you.